<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>PNP on Mathias Osterkamp</title><link>https://conception365.com/tags/pnp/</link><description>Recent content in PNP on Mathias Osterkamp</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://conception365.com/tags/pnp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>PnP Powershell 2019 Documentation</title><link>https://conception365.com/post/2024-01-28-pnp-powwershell-2019-onpremise-docs/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://conception365.com/post/2024-01-28-pnp-powwershell-2019-onpremise-docs/</guid><description>PnP Powershell 2019 Documentation Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s Patterns and Practices (PnP) initiative is a set of community-driven guidelines, practices, and libraries that aim to help developers build better solutions on the Microsoft 365 and SharePoint platforms. As part of the PnP initiative, PowerShell commands have been developed to simplify the management and automation of tasks within these ecosystems. This collection of PowerShell cmdlets is known as Microsoft PnP PowerShell. In this article, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore the documentation resources available for Microsoft PnP PowerShell, providing developers with a valuable guide to mastering this powerful toolset.</description></item><item><title>SPFX 2019 Libraries with PnP JS</title><link>https://conception365.com/post/2021-03-20-spfx-2019-libraries/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://conception365.com/post/2021-03-20-spfx-2019-libraries/</guid><description>What we create Ok. Here a small preview, what we like to create in this guide. A sample webpart loading your code from a library, here together with PnP JS to get all site groups.
You find the complete source code for the solution here.
What are SPFX libraries? If we come to the library topic most people start with the default description from microsoft. (source)
The library component type in the SharePoint Framework (SPFx) enables you to have independently versioned and deployed code served automatically for the SharePoint Framework components with a deployment through an app catalog.</description></item><item><title>Remove Managed Metadata Orphaned Terms</title><link>https://conception365.com/post/2021-02-11-orphaned-terms/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://conception365.com/post/2021-02-11-orphaned-terms/</guid><description>Problem In some cases you like to get rid of orphaned terms. Terms mostly get orphaned, if you reuse terms and delete the original instances. There is a very good explanation from Mike Morawski how this could happen.
Not long ago I was working away with the term store though Powershell. I had to remove all of a particular group’s termsets and to do this I ended up calling the Group’s delete function.</description></item></channel></rss>