<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Administration on Mathias Osterkamp</title><link>https://conception365.com/categories/administration/</link><description>Recent content in Administration on Mathias Osterkamp</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://conception365.com/categories/administration/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Powershell - Create Navigation</title><link>https://conception365.com/post/2021-11-01-powershell-create-navigation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://conception365.com/post/2021-11-01-powershell-create-navigation/</guid><description>Managed Navigation with Powershell Goal Our goal is a complete setup for a test site collection with managed metadata navigation and existing pages with different levels. The challenge is the correct configuration for the site with powershell and also create the correct terms. With the script you can set the amount of navigation entries.
Preparation We use SharePoint PnP Powershell Package to get help with some tasks.
PnP Powershell 2019 Download CSOM dlls &amp;ldquo;Microsoft.</description></item><item><title>SharePoint Server Subscription Edition - First Review</title><link>https://conception365.com/post/2021-07-23-spse-first-review/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://conception365.com/post/2021-07-23-spse-first-review/</guid><description>New SharePoint OnPremise Version Four days ago a new SharePoint OnPremise version is released for preview. It is called SharePoint Server Subscription Edition and comes with some promising headlines:
Today we’re excited to open the window to our vision, strategy, and future for SharePoint and provide a first look at the most recent developments with SharePoint Server.
We designed SharePoint Server SE around the core principles of: Always up to date, Secure and reliable, Designed for you</description></item><item><title>Migrate User Profile My Links</title><link>https://conception365.com/post/2021-05-06-import-export-userprofilelinks/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://conception365.com/post/2021-05-06-import-export-userprofilelinks/</guid><description>Problem SharePoint users can store favorite links directly inside the mysite. If you like to migrate to another SharePoint version or different server maybe you like to transfer these links without copy the database. In general these links are stored in the ProfileDB of your server. There is a smart article about this from Vinods source.
Here a small sample, where you can edit links:
source
Solution I wrote a improved script to import and export the data via xml.</description></item><item><title>Remove Managed Metadata Orphaned Terms</title><link>https://conception365.com/post/2021-02-11-orphaned-terms/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://conception365.com/post/2021-02-11-orphaned-terms/</guid><description>Problem In some cases you like to get rid of orphaned terms. Terms mostly get orphaned, if you reuse terms and delete the original instances. There is a very good explanation from Mike Morawski how this could happen.
Not long ago I was working away with the term store though Powershell. I had to remove all of a particular group’s termsets and to do this I ended up calling the Group’s delete function.</description></item><item><title>Managed Metadata Migration</title><link>https://conception365.com/post/2020-12-12-managed-metadata-migration/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://conception365.com/post/2020-12-12-managed-metadata-migration/</guid><description>Managed metadata is a formal taxonomy classification system. A taxonomy groups the words, labels, and terms that describe something, and then arranges the groups into a hierarchy. You can learn more basics and wordings on microsoft docs. Mostly it is simple called term store.
Where are my data stored? The first common question for migration is, where actual the term store data are stored. The short answer is, everything important is stored in Managed Metadata SQL Database of the service application.</description></item></channel></rss>