<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Mathias Osterkamp</title><link>https://conception365.com/</link><description>Recent content on Mathias Osterkamp</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://conception365.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>SPFX 2019 Custom Installer</title><link>https://conception365.com/post/2021-05-19-spfx-2019-custominstaller/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://conception365.com/post/2021-05-19-spfx-2019-custominstaller/</guid><description>What we create In SharePoint SPFX solution development you have most time the requirement to do some installation tasks. You have multiple solutions for that problem. First - most content can be deployed via XML manifest files to your website. This helps you with the most basic stuff, but if you like to do some more modifications, for example set special permissions on lists or deploy webparts to your page, it have to be done extra.</description></item><item><title>Migrate User Profile My Links</title><link>https://conception365.com/post/2021-05-06-import-export-userprofilelinks/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://conception365.com/post/2021-05-06-import-export-userprofilelinks/</guid><description>Problem SharePoint users can store favorite links directly inside the mysite. If you like to migrate to another SharePoint version or different server maybe you like to transfer these links without copy the database. In general these links are stored in the ProfileDB of your server. There is a smart article about this from Vinods source.
Here a small sample, where you can edit links:
source
Solution I wrote a improved script to import and export the data via xml.</description></item><item><title>PowerApps TimeTracking for SevDesk Part 2</title><link>https://conception365.com/post/2021-05-02-powerapps-sevdesk-technic/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://conception365.com/post/2021-05-02-powerapps-sevdesk-technic/</guid><description>This article continues with technical details about my first part PowerApps TimeTracking for SevDesk. You have full access to the source code inside Office 365 PowerApps.
Custom connector In general in PowerApps you need a data source for every app. This can be done by custom entities or with connectors. O365 brings you a lot of default connectors, if you have a third party system like SevDesk, you can create your own connector.</description></item><item><title>PowerApps TimeTracking for SevDesk</title><link>https://conception365.com/post/2021-04-30-powerapps-sevdesk-guide/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://conception365.com/post/2021-04-30-powerapps-sevdesk-guide/</guid><description>I was looking for a smart and simple mobile time tracking solution connected to SevDesk. SevDesk has no mobile solution for time tracking module. Existing third party apps where not fully fit my requirements. I was satisfied with the default module and implemented a mobile app with Office 365 - PowerApps.
Source: sevdesk.de
This was done a while a go, but I decided now to publish the sources to help you build your own.</description></item><item><title>SPFX 2019 eslint and prettier</title><link>https://conception365.com/post/2021-04-22-spfx-2019-prettier-eslint/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://conception365.com/post/2021-04-22-spfx-2019-prettier-eslint/</guid><description>For our current projects we used tslint and suffered for some problems. First main concern was, that VSCode was not able to give full feedback about code problems. Later on execution of gulp build all errors where thrown. Furthermore we got some conflicts with prettier solution and it was a hell to understand the current used rules from tslint. Also the tslint performance was very awful. We know it is deprecated for a while source and now its time to get rid of it.</description></item><item><title>SPFX 2019 Libraries with PnP JS</title><link>https://conception365.com/post/2021-03-20-spfx-2019-libraries/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://conception365.com/post/2021-03-20-spfx-2019-libraries/</guid><description>What we create Ok. Here a small preview, what we like to create in this guide. A sample webpart loading your code from a library, here together with PnP JS to get all site groups.
You find the complete source code for the solution here.
What are SPFX libraries? If we come to the library topic most people start with the default description from microsoft. (source)
The library component type in the SharePoint Framework (SPFx) enables you to have independently versioned and deployed code served automatically for the SharePoint Framework components with a deployment through an app catalog.</description></item><item><title>Remove Managed Metadata Orphaned Terms</title><link>https://conception365.com/post/2021-02-11-orphaned-terms/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://conception365.com/post/2021-02-11-orphaned-terms/</guid><description>Problem In some cases you like to get rid of orphaned terms. Terms mostly get orphaned, if you reuse terms and delete the original instances. There is a very good explanation from Mike Morawski how this could happen.
Not long ago I was working away with the term store though Powershell. I had to remove all of a particular group’s termsets and to do this I ended up calling the Group’s delete function.</description></item><item><title>Managed Metadata Migration</title><link>https://conception365.com/post/2020-12-12-managed-metadata-migration/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://conception365.com/post/2020-12-12-managed-metadata-migration/</guid><description>Managed metadata is a formal taxonomy classification system. A taxonomy groups the words, labels, and terms that describe something, and then arranges the groups into a hierarchy. You can learn more basics and wordings on microsoft docs. Mostly it is simple called term store.
Where are my data stored? The first common question for migration is, where actual the term store data are stored. The short answer is, everything important is stored in Managed Metadata SQL Database of the service application.</description></item><item><title>About me</title><link>https://conception365.com/top/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://conception365.com/top/about/</guid><description>WHO AM I? SharePoint / Office 365 / Azure Specialist I&amp;rsquo;ve been working for about 10 years with a thematic focus on &amp;ldquo;Collaboration&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Digital Transformation&amp;rdquo; especially in the product environment Microsoft on the topics Office 365, SharePoint, Azure and general web development.
WHAT I DO? Conception, Consulting, Implementation Based on my experience i create concepts and solutions by following modern architecture and programming trends. By transfering my knowlegde you will get future proved work for your company.</description></item><item><title>Impressum</title><link>https://conception365.com/top/impressum/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://conception365.com/top/impressum/</guid><description>Angaben gemäß § 5 TMG
Mathias Osterkamp
Flossmannstr. 2
81245 München
GERMANY
Kontakt E-Mail: mathias.osterkamp@conception365.com
Wir sind nicht bereit oder verpflichtet, an Streitbeilegungsverfahren vor einer Verbraucherschlichtungsstelle teilzunehmen.
Haftung für Inhalte
Als Diensteanbieter sind wir gemäß § 7 Abs.1 TMG für eigene Inhalte auf diesen Seiten nach den allgemeinen Gesetzen verantwortlich. Nach §§ 8 bis 10 TMG sind wir als Diensteanbieter jedoch nicht verpflichtet, übermittelte oder gespeicherte fremde Informationen zu überwachen oder nach Umständen zu forschen, die auf eine rechtswidrige Tätigkeit hinweisen.</description></item><item><title>Privacy Policy</title><link>https://conception365.com/top/privacy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://conception365.com/top/privacy/</guid><description>Privacy Policy We are very delighted that you have shown interest in our enterprise. Data protection is of a particularly high priority for the management of the Mathias Osterkamp. The use of the Internet pages of the Mathias Osterkamp is possible without any indication of personal data; however, if a data subject wants to use special enterprise services via our website, processing of personal data could become necessary. If the processing of personal data is necessary and there is no statutory basis for such processing, we generally obtain consent from the data subject.</description></item><item><title>Search Results</title><link>https://conception365.com/search/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://conception365.com/search/</guid><description>let params = { json_src: "/index.json", minlength: 3, defaultsearch: "AND", sort_date: "DESC", autocomplete: 1, section_search: 0, badwords: "and, or", json_wait: "One moment search is loading...
", json_ready: "Please enter a search term
", extern_icon: " (externer Link)", err_badstring: "Your searchterm is to short!
", err_noresult: "No result found.
", err_norequest: 'Fulltext search is not available.
', err_filefailed: 'Search file not found.
', res_one_item: "[CNT] Searchresult
", res_more_items: "</description></item></channel></rss>