<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Mathias Osterkamp</title><link>https://conception365.com/</link><description>Recent content on Mathias Osterkamp</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://conception365.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>SPFX 2019 eslint and prettier</title><link>https://conception365.com/post/2021-04-22-spfx-2019-prettier-eslint/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://conception365.com/post/2021-04-22-spfx-2019-prettier-eslint/</guid><description>SPFX 2019 eslint and prettier For our current projects we used tslint and suffered for some problems. First main concern was, that VSCode was not able to give full feedback about code problems. Later on execution of gulp build all errors where thrown. Furthermore we got some conflicts with prettier solution and it was a hell to understand the current used rules from tslint. Also the tslint performance was very awful.</description></item><item><title>Remove Managed Metadata Orphaned Terms</title><link>https://conception365.com/post/2021-02-11-orphaned-terms/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://conception365.com/post/2021-02-11-orphaned-terms/</guid><description>Remove Managed Metadata Orphaned Terms Problem In some cases you like to get rid of orphaned terms. Terms mostly get orphaned, if you reuse terms and delete the original instances. There is a very good explanation from Mike Morawski how this could happen.
Not long ago I was working away with the term store though Powershell. I had to remove all of a particular group’s termsets and to do this I ended up calling the Group’s delete function.</description></item><item><title>Managed Metadata Migration</title><link>https://conception365.com/post/2020-12-12-managed-metadata-migration/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://conception365.com/post/2020-12-12-managed-metadata-migration/</guid><description>Managed Metadata Migration Managed metadata is a formal taxonomy classification system. A taxonomy groups the words, labels, and terms that describe something, and then arranges the groups into a hierarchy. You can learn more basics and wordings on microsoft docs. Mostly it is simple called term store.
Where are my data stored? The first common question for migration is, where actual the term store data are stored. The short answer is, everything important is stored in Managed Metadata SQL Database of the service application.</description></item><item><title>About me</title><link>https://conception365.com/top/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://conception365.com/top/about/</guid><description>WHO AM I? SharePoint / Office 365 / Azure Specialist I&amp;rsquo;ve been working for about 10 years with a thematic focus on &amp;ldquo;Collaboration&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Digital Transformation&amp;rdquo; especially in the product environment Microsoft on the topics Office 365, SharePoint, Azure and general web development.
WHAT I DO? Conception, Consulting, Implementation Based on my experience i create concepts and solutions by following modern architecture and programming trends. By transfering my knowlegde you will get future proved work for your company.</description></item><item><title>Impressum</title><link>https://conception365.com/top/impressum/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://conception365.com/top/impressum/</guid><description>Angaben gemäß § 5 TMG
Mathias Osterkamp
Flossmannstr. 2
81245 München
GERMANY
Kontakt E-Mail: mathias.osterkamp@conception365.com
Wir sind nicht bereit oder verpflichtet, an Streitbeilegungsverfahren vor einer Verbraucherschlichtungsstelle teilzunehmen.
Haftung für Inhalte
Als Diensteanbieter sind wir gemäß § 7 Abs.1 TMG für eigene Inhalte auf diesen Seiten nach den allgemeinen Gesetzen verantwortlich. Nach §§ 8 bis 10 TMG sind wir als Diensteanbieter jedoch nicht verpflichtet, übermittelte oder gespeicherte fremde Informationen zu überwachen oder nach Umständen zu forschen, die auf eine rechtswidrige Tätigkeit hinweisen.</description></item><item><title>Privacy Policy</title><link>https://conception365.com/top/privacy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://conception365.com/top/privacy/</guid><description>Privacy Policy We are very delighted that you have shown interest in our enterprise. Data protection is of a particularly high priority for the management of the Mathias Osterkamp. The use of the Internet pages of the Mathias Osterkamp is possible without any indication of personal data; however, if a data subject wants to use special enterprise services via our website, processing of personal data could become necessary. If the processing of personal data is necessary and there is no statutory basis for such processing, we generally obtain consent from the data subject.</description></item><item><title>Search Results</title><link>https://conception365.com/search/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://conception365.com/search/</guid><description>let params = { json_src: "/index.json", minlength: 3, defaultsearch: "AND", sort_date: "DESC", autocomplete: 1, section_search: 0, badwords: "and, or", json_wait: "One moment search is loading...
", json_ready: "Please enter a search term
", extern_icon: " (externer Link)", err_badstring: "Your searchterm is to short!
", err_noresult: "No result found.
", err_norequest: 'Fulltext search is not available.
', err_filefailed: 'Search file not found.
', res_one_item: "[CNT] Searchresult
", res_more_items: "</description></item></channel></rss>